so what is it that enables the wise to
do what they hear it's not otherwise
like I will do it and foolish Ally I
don't want to do it the difference is
that the wise have oil in them and the
oil in them enables them to do while the
foolish cannot do because they have no
oil in their vessels my servant did fear
the Lord and the creditor has come to
take unto him my two sons to be bond men
have you ever been in a place in your
life where it feels like things are not
going too well
this woman has just lost her husband and
now the creditors are coming to take her
sons as bond men think that all of us or
most of us can relate to going through
serious things in our lives this woman
the Bible says she cried unto Elisha let
me ask you have you ever cried unto the
Lord
she says Elisha you know that my husband
feared the Lord it's as if she is trying
to remind Elisha that this family was a
good family
I think of Psalms 103 11 the Bible says
for as the heavens is high above the
earth so great is his mercy toward them
that what fear him so where is the mercy
for my family you know my husband feared
the Lord where is God's mercy in my time
of need verse
13 of the same chapter like a father
pitieth his children so the Lord pities
of them that what fear him verse 17 of
the same chapter but the mercy of the
Lord is from everlasting to everlasting
upon them that what fear him and his
righteousness unto children's children
it's as if she's trying to say to Elisha
listen the Lord promises mercy to those
that fear Him and you know that my
family feared the Lord and yet here we
are in this situation Psalm 112 verses 1
through 3 praising the Lord blessed is
the man that what fear at the Lord that
the light of greatly in his commandments
his seed shall be mighty upon the earth
the generations of the upright shall be
blessed wealth and what riches shall be
in his house and his righteousness
endureth for ever but if you know this
story this woman is not only no longer
does she have a husband but she is what
kind of a woman a poor woman she has
nothing where is the promise of God the
second Kings chapter 4 and verse 2 and
Elisha said unto her what shall I do
finis tell me what hast thou in the and
she said unhand maid has not anything in
the house
save what a pot of oil
the title of the sermon is very simple
what you have nothing left when you have
nothing left let me ask you have you
ever felt like you had nothing left I'm
not talking about physical things I'm
not talking about finances I'm not
talking about
things you can touch but have you ever
gotten to the place in your walk where
you felt like you had not much left to
give this woman is having this
experience she says I have nothing left
in my house
save this pot of oil we're not told how
she got into this condition but we know
how we get into this condition you see
for some of us it could be that verse in
John chapter 10 verse 10 where where the
Bible says the thief cometh not but for
to steal and to kill and to destroy so
the written of nothing left to share
when it comes to your Christianity is
that Satan has come in and he has stolen
your joy ever experience that he's
stolen your peace he's stolen your love
he's stolen your fire he might have
stolen her health or your finances or
your marriage and you feel like you are
in poverty you have nothing left second
Timothy chapter 3 verse 12 tells us yay
all that live godly in Christ Jesus
shall suffer what persecution but you
kind of feel like man this is too much
for me ever feel like persecution is too
much for you or maybe you have nothing
left because you left it on your own
revelation 2 verse 4 remember the words
of Jesus where he said never
nevertheless I have somewhat against
thee because thou has left thy first
ones love so there was a time that you
were in love with God a time that you
were on fire for God but you left that
first love and it was probably because
you fell asleep proverbs 20 verse 13 the
Bible says love not sleep lest thou come
to what poverty
open thine eyes and thou shalt be
satisfied with bread you remember the
parable that Jesus gave in Matthew 13:24
where he says the kingdom of heaven is
likened to unto a man which sowed good
seed in his field but while men want
slept the enemy came and sowed tares
among the wheat and went his way so
maybe it is just that you fell asleep
and asleep led you to poverty and so now
you come to the place where you realize
you have not much left in your Christian
walk or maybe it is just that sin has
poverty the Bible says the wages of sin
is ones is that sin leaves you in debt
and so your struggle with that addiction
with that besetting sin that thing that
you keep doing over and over again that
you promise no more no more and yet you
continue to do it makes you feel as if
the creditor is coming to get you you
have nothing left to give
and Elijah's response is interesting
because he says what shall I do for thee
it's like he's asking what do you want
me to do for you because this woman is
coming and crying out because of her
great need let me ask you have you ever
cried out to God or have you ever cried
out in that great need and and and how
many of you would love for God to say
what shall I do for you we're coming to
him in our great need and we wish he
would say these words what shall I do
for you and I want to share with you
listen this is God's promise because the
Bible says in Psalms 18 verse 6 it says
in my distress I called upon the Lord
and cried unto my God and he heard my
voice out of his temple and my cry came
before him he
and unto his ears I want to let you know
that when you cry out to God he is going
to hear you when you cry out to God he
is going to answer you even when you
feel like he is not listening cry out to
God because He will give you the answer
and I'm gonna share with you right now
that if you're here today I believe God
has an answer for you you may be crying
out because of your experience you may
be saying lord I don't you know when I
first came into this church when I was
first outside I was just so excited
about you and excited about your word
and excited about serving but now I just
feel like I have nothing left I feel
like I'm just floating along I feel like
I am in party and I need you to do
something for me because my debt is
greater than I can pay in 2nd Kings
chapter 4 and verse 3 I want you to
notice this because this is very this is
this is absolutely amazing eyes I have a
very simple point I don't want to get
across to you today and I want you to
notice the 2nd 2nd Kings chapter 4 verse
3 then he said go he said whatever you
want go go borrow thee watts
vessels abroad of all thy neighbors even
watts
empty vessels borrow not a few how many
people know the story right the story
right she goes and she she goes to her
neighbors and she's bringing in all
these empty vessels into her house verse
4 verse 4 the Bible says and when thou
are come in thou shall shut the door
upon thee and upon thy sons and shall
wot pour out into all those vessels and
thou shalt set aside that which is full
now pause for a second does that make
sense who just said yes
alright you're right it makes sense and
in a sense it does not make sense it
doesn't make sense in our human sense
but it made sense in divine sense
because all of this lady has is what one
pot of oil and Elijah says I want you to
take that pot of oil and I want you to
gather as many empty vessels as you can
and I want you to begin to want to pour
and I want you to fill those vessels
that does not make sense humanly
speaking because it's only one pot it's
all that this woman has left notice
verse five so she went from him and shut
the door upon her and upon her sons who
brought the vessels to her and she wants
she Ford she poured I want you to notice
something very very profound yet very
simple
this woman was living in an empty house
when she came crying to Elisha
her focus was on her hid her empty house
and Elisha says I want you to turn your
focus to empty vessels i nee i want you
to focus on what i just said i want you
to turn your focus on empty vessels
outside of your home i want you to go to
your neighbors and i want you to get to
get in touch with their empty vessels
and i want you to bring those empty
vessels into your own house see it
elisha wanted her to turn
her attention from her own emptiness to
an emptiness outside of her something in
her turning her attention from her own
Antonis and her own suffering to the two
empty vessels outside was going to be a
part of the process of her healing
interesting the Bible says in Matthew
chapter 10 verse 39 and this might might
really come home to you he that findeth
his life shall lose it and he that one
loses his life for my sake shall find it
in other words he that does not focus on
his own needs and his own life but
focuses on other things will find his
life but he that focuses on himself or
herself will end up what losing that
life elisha is trying to get her to
focus on other empty vessels what am i
trying to say to you
God is calling you to stop focusing on
your own Auntie vessel and start
focusing on other empty vessels because
in focusing on other empty vessels
something will begin to happen to your
vessel the Bible says she break these
vessels in by the way Joel chapter 2
verse 20 I think we can get it up on the
screen did Jesus give us a promise he
did here's what the promise said it
shall come to pass afterward that I will
want I will pour out my spirit upon all
flesh give me another term for that
please all what empty
vessels but over Jesus Christ you might
say symbolized that pot of oil that one
source of oil through which all other
vessels must be filled when Jesus came
to this world he came to do something
very special he came to fill empty
vessels but neither you and I before we
came to Christ we were empty vessels and
Jesus Christ that one source one man it
just doesn't seem like one man can fill
an entire world of vessels and yet that
one man did through his sacrifice Jesus
says I have filled you with my power
with my grace and galatians chapter 2
verse 20 the bible says speaking of
jesus galatians chapter 2 verse 20 I'm
crucified with Christ nevertheless I
live yet not i but Christ liveth in me
and the life which I now live in the
flesh I live by the faith of the Son of
God who loved me and what poured himself
out for me gave himself for me beloved
the life that we live the spirit that is
in us is because Jesus gave it to us in
him is sufficient spirit for every
person in this place and every person on
this earth this is why the Bible says in
2nd Corinthians chapter 4 verse 7 second
is for seven it says but we have this
what treasure in earthen vessels that
the excellency of the power may be of
God and none of us
what are these earthen vessels and what
is the treasure it's Jesus
it's his spirit dwelling in us that's
the treasure that's what the wealth and
the riches are how many of you would
like to be wealthy how many of you would
like to be rich
the Bible says remember we read it
earlier those that fear the Lord wealth
and riches shall be in their house how
many of you want to be wealthy how many
of you want to be rich
beloved true wealth and true richness
comes when the Spirit of God fills you
when you are no longer an empty vessel
but a net but a vessel filled with the
Spirit of God so now we're beginning to
understand beloved that in if I want to
be filled
I must pour into others did you catch
what I just said if I want the oil in me
if I want to be filled with the spirit
then I must focus on pouring that spirit
out to others this is very significant
for us to understand another because
there's a parable given in Matthew 25
where there are five wise virgins and
five foolish virgins
all of them have vessels but five of
them have no what no oil how many of you
remember in the parable are in the story
of this woman that when she as long as
she had empty vessels and she was
pouring out more oil continued to flow
but the moment the vessels were filled
the moment she stopped pouring the oil
stopped want flowing please catch that
point the moment she stopped pouring the
oil stopped flowing could it be that the
five foolish virgins stopped being
interested in others and were only
interested in self
how many of you want to be wise Jesus
says in Matthew 7 you got to catch this
Matthew 7 verse 24 Matthew chapter 7
verse 24 to 27 therefore whosoever
heareth these sayings of mine and what
and what everyone do with them so it's
not just about hearing it's about doing
says I will liken him on toy into a wise
man that built his house upon a rock and
the rain descended and the floods came
and the winds blew and beat upon that
house and it fell not for it was founded
upon a rock why was it founded upon a
rock because not only did they hear but
they want but they did okay now what
doesn't that say next and everyone that
hears these sayings of mine and doeth
them what not shall be likened unto a
foolish man which built his house upon
the Lord sand and the rain descended and
the floods came and the winds blew and
beat upon that house and it fell and
great was the fall of it so what is the
difference between the wise and the
foolish they both hear but one does not
want do so the question is why what if
what makes the wise do when the foolish
do not the what the spirit won't come
see this notice with me Galatians
chapter I'm sorry zechariah chapter 4
we're gonna read one through zechariah
chapter four one two six isness and the
angel talk with me came again and walked
with me as a man that is wake waked me
as a man that is waken out of his sleep
verse two and seven to me what sees them
and i said i said i looked and behold a
candlestick all of gold with a bowl on
the top of it and is seven lamps thereon
and seven pipes to the lamps which are
upon the top there are verse three and
two olive trees buying it one upon the
right side of the bowl the other upon
the left side of it verse four so I
answered and speak to the angel that
talked with me saying what are these my
lord verse 5 then the angel talked
me and answered and said knowest not
what these V and I said no my lord verse
6 then he answered and said unto me this
is the word of the Lord to Zerubbabel
saying not by might nor by power but by
my want spirits say the Lord let me let
me rephrase what we just heard here
Zechariah seizes vision a candlestick
and on two sides are these olive trees
and the olive trees are emptying what is
this an angel says listen this light
burns not by might nor by what power but
by my what spirit so what is it that
enables the wise to do what they hear
it's not otherwise look like I will do
it and foolish a light I don't want to
do it the difference is that the wise
have oil in them and the oil in them
enables them to do while the foolish
cannot do because they have no oil in
their vessels when the oil is in you it
is f that the love of God is flowing
through you why because you are pouring
yourself into others you are giving of
yourself and God is trying to show us
listen you want the spirit flowing
through you you can only do it by
possessing love because only by love can
we actually give ourselves for others
and God has simply said I want you to
love see the opposite of love is
selfishness and with selfishness all you
do is focus upon self but love enables
you love moves you to focus on others to
pour out for others this is why
galatians 5:22 says this the fruit of
the Spirit is what
is love joy peace longsuffering
gentleness goodness faith meekness
temperance all of these things beloved
represent the fruit of the Spirit now
watch this this woman was called to
bring empty vessels into her house I
need you to focus on that for a second
this woman woman woman was called to
bring empty vessels into her vessel
and they're out love joy peace
longsuffering gentleness goodness faith
and and the story goes that as long as
she did this the oil was flowing you see
God has given us a commission and it is
found in Matthew 28 go ye into all the
world just like he told this woman go
get vessels it's the city it's the
gospel Commission Revelation chapter 14
verse 6 I saw another angel flying in
the midst of heaven having a vessel full
of oil to pour out to the whole world we
are that vessel God has filled us so
that we can pour out and fill others and
he says as you do this when you do this
what will happen is that my spirit will
continue to flow through you I think
that's what we're all after is now right
we all want that Spirit of God to be
flowing through us and God says you get
it by giving it you get it by giving it
so let's go back to 2nd Kings we're
gonna wrap this up 2nd Kings chapter 4
verse 6 I want you to notice what it
says here 2nd Kings chapter 4 verse 6 it
came to pass when the vessels were full
that she said to her son bring me yet a
vessel and he said unto her there is not
a vessel more and the oil was stayed let
me share something with you when the
last vessel on planet earth is filled
the oil will cease to flow did you catch
what I just said
when the lacz vessel on earth is filled
that is when the Spirit of God is
withdrawn we have a mission bring as
many vessels into the house of God fill
them and when the last vessel is filled
the Spirit will cease to be given out on
earth but before that time God's trying
to tell us now you stop pouring and
you're gonna stop receiving oil keep
pouring
keep pouring yourself into other people
keep pouring yourself into others keep
looking for empty vessels and keep
looking for people to pour your love
your joy your peace your happiness and
because by doing that you will multiply
your own joy own peace and your own
happiness verse 7 our last verse then
she came and told the man of God and he
said go sell the oil and do what pay
your debt
and live thou and thy children off the
rest but ever when the Spirit of God
flows through you you have enough to pay
off that debt of sin that's what we're
all after pay the debt of sin it's not
you paying it's the Spirit of God are
you with me the Spirit of God cancels
that dead not only does a counselor dead
but I am enough for you to live off for
the rest of your life you have me you
will not need anything else
[Music]
give you all that's all these sun us
love with how much oh lord I only have a
little less use that little I only have
a little the Bible says God has given
every man a measure of faith so if your
faith is the size of a mustard seed use
that faith and God will multiply it love
the Lord your God with all your heart